<postsArchive>

<!-- 
    Stucure of an entry
<POST>
    <title>Title of the position</title>
    <number>number of available positions</number>
    <type>either phd for PhD students, post for postdocs, prof for tenure</type>
    <description>description of the position</description>
    <where>Hosting institution</where>
    <when>Date of publishing the annuncment in the form "dd/mm/yyyy" </when>
    <link>link of the official position announcement</link>
    <deadline>deadline for application in the form "dd/mm/yyyy" </deadline>
</POST> 

    Do not remove previous posts.
    Add new post right below here.
-->


<POST>
    <title>Fully funded PhD position on Axiomatic Definitions (Aix-en-Provence/Marseille, Francia)</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>phd</type>
    <description>
        Fully funded PhD position in "Axiomatic definitions. Criteria of adequacy and typologies of definitions in axiomatic theories of 19th and 20th centuries". Centre Gilles Gaston Granger, University of Aix-Marseille. Part of the ANR project AXDEF led by Paola Cantù.
    </description>
    <where>Centre Gilles Gaston Granger, University of Aix-Marseille</where>
    <when>29/05/2024</when>
    <link>https://emploi.cnrs.fr/Offres/Doctorant/UMR7304-PAOCAN-001/Default.aspx?lang=EN</link>
    <deadline>03/06/2024</deadline>
</POST>


<POST>
    <title>Three 2-year postdocs (Milano, IT)</title>
    <number>3</number>
    <type>post</type>
    <description>
        The Logic Uncertainty Computation and Information (LUCI) Lab at the University of Milan is seeking applications for   
        Three 2-year postdoctoral positions 
        funded by the Italian Ministry of University and Research (MUR) under the FIS1 Advanced Grant Reasoning with Data (ReDa)  led by Hykel Hosni 

        Deadline for application: 4 June 2024 
        Expected starting date:  1 September 2024 (negotiable)

        The appointments. Appointments will be made in either of the work packages below. Please specify in your application which WP would suit you best. Each candidate can put in one application only.  There are no teaching duties attached to the posts, and proficiency in Italian is not required. 
        Work package 1:  Non-monotonic formalisation of data-driven inference.
        The appointee is expected to work on the identification of suitable constraints for consequence relations capable of expressing salient patterns of data-driven inference. (The background and general idea are discussed informally here https://projects.illc.uva.nl/lgc/seminar/2023/03/lira-session-hykel-hosni/) . 
        Candidates for this work package must have a strong background in logic, acquired through a Master and a PhD in any of the relevant paths, including and possibly combining, Mathematics, Philosophy, and Computer Science. Familiarity with the preferential approach to nonmonotonic reasoning is a plus. Applicants are also expected to be conversant with elementary probability and statistics. 
        Work package 2:  Logic for the methodology of data-intensive and AI-driven science
        The appointee is expected to identify suitable roles for logical methods in the construction of a scientific methodology capable of encompassing AI-driven science. Logicians have traditionally followed Tarski in restricting the applicability of logic to the methodology of deductive sciences. In the age of data-intensive and machine-learning-driven science, this is overly restrictive both for logic and for science. To overcome this, the appointee will pin down patterns reasoning from any area of data-intensive and AI-driven science (preferably biology) and work towards their logical formalisation.
        Candidates for this work package must have a strong background in logic or philosophy of science, preferably both, acquired through a Master and a PhD in any of the relevant subject. Familiarity with the methodological and epistemological questions revolving around “big data” are a definite plus. Applicants are also expected to be conversant with the current literature on AI for scientific research, including explainable AI. Familiarity with the history of logic from Boole onwards is desirable.
        Work package 3:  The construction of probabilistic evidence in rare cancers
        The successful candidate is expected to work on methodologically rigorous approaches to the personalisation of probability in clinical decision-making about rare cancers. The key goal is to put forward principled ways to come up with patient-specific, meaningful, probabilities from data about “the average patient” arising in clinical studies. Since this work package will contribute to developing decision-theoretic tools to be used at the patient’s bedside, the appointed researcher will be based at the Istituto Nazionale Tumori in Milan, and will work in close collaboration with the Biostatistics for Clinical Research, Sarcomas, and Head-and-Neck Cancers Units.   
        Applicants for this WP must have a strong background in medical statistics, clinical epidemiology and probability applied to those fields, acquired through any relevant postgraduate degree. Familiarity with medical decision making and the construction of probabilistic and statistical evidence is a definite plus.

        How to apply
        Please read carefully the official call for the posts, which is available in Italian and in English at 
        https://www.unimi.it/it/ricerca/ricerca-lastatale/fare-ricerca-da-noi/assegni-e-borse/bandi-assegni-di-ricerca/bando-di-tipo-b-prof-hosni-id-6648
    </description>
    <where>UNIMI</where>
    <when>29/05/2024</when>
    <link>https://luci.unimi.it/open-positions/</link>
    <deadline>04/06/2024</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>Chaire de Professeur Junior (Clermont-Ferrand, France)</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>prof</type>
    <description>
        Un poste de "Chaire de Professeur Junior" va être ouvert pour la rentrée prochaine au Laboratoire de Mathématiques Blaise Pascal de l'Université Clermont Auvergne (avec comité de sélection en septembre, et prise de fonction en novembre). Il sera publié prochainement sur Galaxie, et les candidatures seront ouvertes jusqu'à fin juin. Le profil recherché est en "Algèbre et théorie des représentations", mais toutes les candidatures dans des domaines connexes pouvant s'intégrer au laboratoire (notamment topologie, théorie des nombres, théorie des groupes, analyse harmonique non commutative) seront étudiées avec attention.
        
        [Consultare la scadenza sul sito!]
    </description>
    <where>Université Clermont Auvergne</where>
    <when>22/05/2024</when>
    <link>https://lmbp.uca.fr/emplois/index.php</link>
    <deadline>30/06/2024</deadline>
</POST> 


<POST>
    <title>PhD program in Mathematics (Torino, Italy)</title>
    <number>7</number>
    <type>phd</type>
    <description>
        There are 7 positions with fellowship and one of them is specifically reserved for candidates with a foreign master degree. It is possible to have joint supervision with a partner university
    </description>
    <where>Università di Torino</where>
    <when>22/05/2024</when>
    <link>https://www.dottorato.unito.it/do/home.pl/View?doc=Bando_XL_ciclo.html</link>
    <deadline>20/06/2024</deadline>
</POST> 

<POST>
    <title>PhD program in Mathematics and Physics (Udine, Italy)</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>phd</type>
    <description>
        In 2024 we are especially interested in students willing to work in set theory (potential supervisor Vincenzo Dimonte) and connections with dynamical systems (potential supervisor Giovanni Panti). Udine’s Mathematical Logic group consists also of one post-doc researcher and two active PhD students (two others will obtain their degrees in 2024). You can contact any of us if you have further queries about possible scientific projects. For administrative information please contact dottorato.rice@uniud.it
    </description>
    <where>Università di Udine</where>
    <when>21/05/2024</when>
    <link>https://www.dmif.uniud.it/dottorato/smf/</link>
    <deadline>20/06/2024</deadline>
</POST> 

<POST>
    <title>PhD programs (Lucca, Italy)</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>phd</type>
    <description>
        Highly motivated candidates interested in doing philosophical research in a multidisciplinary environment are invited to apply online for scholarships offered by the Cognitive, Computational and Social Neurosciences (CCSN) and Economics, Analytics and Decision Sciences (EADS) doctoral programs at the IMT School for Advanced Studies Lucca (www.imtlucca.it).
        The successful candidates will join the MInD (Models, Inferences, and Decisions) group within the MoMiLab research unit. The ideal candidate will have a strong background in philosophy of science, epistemology, or logic and be interested in multidisciplinary work at the interface between philosophy, cognitive (neuro)science, and (behavioral) economics. Relevant research areas include general and formal philosophy of science, formal and social epistemology, philosophy of the cognitive and behavioral sciences, and theoretical and empirical models of expert judgment and reasoning (see the MInD page for more detail).
        The positions consist of a 3-year studentship of 16.243 euros per year (tax free, social security withholding), free housing in the School’s accessible campus in the historical town of Lucca, free access to the canteen, library and other facilities on campus, additional funds for research and international mobility.
    </description>
    <where>IMT School for Advanced Studies Lucca</where>
    <when>26/05/2024</when>
    <link>https://www.imtlucca.it/en/phd/information-for-students</link>
    <deadline>21/06/2024</deadline>
</POST> 

<POST>
    <title>Assegno di Ricerca (Milano, Italy)</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>post</type>
    <description>Assegno di Ricerca di 18 mesi (supervisor Pr. Ghilardi)</description>
    <where>Università di Milano</where>
    <when>26/05/2024</when>
    <link>https://www.unimi.it/it/ricerca/fare-ricerca-da-noi/assegni-di-ricerca/bandi-assegni-di-ricerca</link>
    <deadline>26/06/2024</deadline>
</POST> 

<POST>
    <title>PhD in Proof Theory (Brighton, UK)</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>phd</type>
    <description>
    The Department of Informatics at the University of Sussex (Brighton, UK) invites applications for highly motivated candidates interested in PhD positions in Logic (Proof Theory).
    The ideal candidate has a Master's degree in Mathematics, Computer Science or Philosophy with experience in Logic (preferably in Proof Theory). 
    The position has a duration of 3.5 years ideally starting in September 2024.
    The hired candidate will be part of the Foundations of Software Systems group ( https://www.sussex.ac.uk/foss/ ), a dynamic group in Theoretical Computer Science which is currently growing and has recently hired various young researchers.

    The project aims at studying the problem of proof equivalence and its applications.
    The problem of proof equivalence, which recently came to the forefront after the discovery of the 24th Hilbert problem, deals with deciding whether two logical arguments should be considered as the same proof, providing theoretical foundations for notions of program equivalences.
    To this end, the project will investigate novel notions of proof equivalence in various logical systems through the lens of proof theory. Emphasis will be given to the study of proof systems allowing canonical representations of proofs (e.g., Hughes' combinatorial proofs and Girard's proof nets). Moreover, the project plans to establish connections between proof equivalence and games, both in the sense of dialogical games (Lorenz and Lorenzen) and game semantics (Abramsky, Hyland and Ong).
    According to the interest of the candidate, applications to interoperability and usability of automated theorem prover and proof assistant, or applications to the theory of programming languages may be investigated.


    Applicants interested in the study of proof theory are encouraged to get in touch with Dr. Matteo Acclavio for additional information and informal inquiries.
    </description>
    <where>University of Sussex</where>
    <when>03/05/2024</when>
    <link>https://www.sussex.ac.uk/study/fees-funding/phd-funding/view/1735-PhD-Informatics-Scholarship-in-Proof-Theory </link>
    <deadline>06/06/2024</deadline>
</POST> 

<POST>
    <title>PhD in linear programming (Paris, France)</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>phd</type>
    <description>
        We seek PhD candidates to a joint program between LIP6-Sorbonne University and the School of Computer Science, University of Sydney. The topic of the thesis will be focused on linear programming techniques in learning-augmented algorithms. 

        Candidate profile:

        * Bachelor's and Master's Degrees in Computer Science or a related discipline such as Mathematics of Operations Research. Specifically, candidates must hold a degree equivalent to a Bologna-complying Master degree with research experience.

        * Strong background and interest in the theoretical analysis of algorithms, documented by coursewor, and ideally past exposure to research on topics such as approximation/online/randomized algorithms, or related algorithmic area.

        * Proficiency in English.


        Candidates should submit, via email to Spyros Angelopoulos (spyros.angelopoulos@lip6.fr) and Julian Mestre (julian.mestre@sydney.edu.au), the following:

        - CV

        - Transcripts of grades for all acquired degrees (for French candidates, this refers to Licence, M1, and M2 degrees. For international candidates, this refers to Bachelor and Master degrees).
        
        - A motivation letter.

        - Letters of recommendation by at least one academic reference, preferably the supervisor of the Master's studies. The letters should be sent directly by the references, and they must be received by the deadline.
    </description>
    <where>LIP6-Sorbonne University (FR) and University of Sydney (AU)</where>
    <when>01/05/2024</when>
    <link></link>
    <deadline>21/05/2024</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>PhD in differential equations for deep learning (Paris, France)</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>phd</type>
    <description>
        We have a doctoral funding available that focuses on the use of differential equation theory (analog computation models) for learning in deep learning. Applications to a physics problem (particle accelerator control). Multidisciplinary context: mathematics, computer science, and applications to physics.
        Keywords: theoretical computer science, complexity, algorithmics, deep learning, applications to physics.
        All applications are welcome, especially those accompanied by a CV, transcripts, and references. Contact <a href="https://www.lri.fr/~jcohen/pages/phd-students.html">Johanne Cohen</a> for information.
    </description>
    <where>University of Paris-Saclay, LISN Laboratory</where>
    <when>01/05/2024</when>
    <link></link>
    <deadline>13/05/2024</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>PhD in Type Theory (Nantes, France)</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>phd</type>
    <description>
        The Gallinette team, hosted by Nantes University, advertises a 3-year PhD position in type theory.
        The position is financed by the ERC (European Research Council) project Fresco, coordinated by Assia Mahboubi. 
        Any candidate with a Master degree in mathematics or computer science and a scientific interest in the topic of the PhD project is encouraged to apply.
        The application should contain a motivation letter, an academic CV, and the contact information of two academic references (name, e-mail, and connection to the applicant). 
        Expected start date: 1 October 2024 (negotiable)
    </description>
    <where>Nantes University, Gallinette team</where>
    <when>01/05/2024</when>
    <link>https://recrutement.inria.fr/public/classic/fr/offres/2024-07624</link>
    <deadline>25/06/2024</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>PhD in Theoretical Computer Science or Operational Research (Paris, France)</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>phd</type>
    <description>
        We seek candidates for a PhD position at  LIP6-Sorbonne University. 
        The position targets applicants with background and interest in at least one of the following domains: Theoretical Computer Science (e.g., approximation, randomized, online algorithms), or Operations Research (e.g., Game Theory, Scheduling). 
        Candidate profile:
        
        * Bachelor's and Master's Degrees in Computer Science or a related discipline such as Mathematics or Operations Research.
        
        * Strong background and interest in theoretical/mathematical topics, as documented by coursework or previous research (ideally).
        
        * Proficiency in English.

        Candidates must consult the web site of the École Doctoral EDITE that provides the funding, in particular the section "Candidatures", which also describes the application procedure and the selection process. All applicants should contact the supervisor, by email, well prior to the deadline, by submitting a CV, transcripts of all courses, and names and contact information of two references. This step is particularly important for international applicants.
    </description>
    <where>AILA</where>
    <when>01/05/2024</when>
    <link>https://myedb.edite-de-paris.fr/PRD_View/8676/</link>
    <deadline>15/05/2024</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>Postdoc in algorithmic and quantitative study of data structures (Caen, France)</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>post</type>
    <description>
        Our project consists of an algorithmic and quantitative study of classical data structures from computer science under the prism of combinatorics. In the last decade many improvements have been achieved in order to characterize the modeling of these data structures as directed acyclic graphs (or DAGs) combinatorially, paving the way for the analysis of objects induced by compaction procedures: in particular, we will focus on Boolean circuits and decision diagrams. The project thus focuses on considering new types of objects in the combinatorial setting. For some of them, even a proper specification is missing and it could be a major challenge to find one. A further challenge is to extend the generating function algebra to these new settings.
        To apply, please, send CV + scientific project (in relation with the project) + any letters of recommendation + possible labs affiliations to Antoine GENITRINI.
    </description>
    <where>GREYC (Normandy University, Caen), LIP6 (Sorbonne University, Paris) or LIPN (Sorbonne Paris Nord University, Villetaneuse)</where>
    <when>01/05/2024</when>
    <link>https://www-apr.lip6.fr/~genitrini/doc_ens/pandag.pdf</link>
    <deadline>15/06/2024</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>PhD in Programming Languages (Odense, Denmark)</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>phd</type>
    <description>
        This position is tied to the ERC Consolidator Project “Choreographies for Distributed Systems: Reasoning, Expressivity, and Development (CHORDS)”. The project aims at introducing new language abstractions, formal models, and software tools for radically changing how we can reason about and develop realistic distributed systems. To this end, the project will establish a collaborative team that will investigate novel theoretical foundations and a formally-verified toolchain for the new paradigm of choreographic programming. The successful candidate will work with the project’s principal investigator (Prof. Fabrizio Montesi), who is a pioneer of the paradigm, and join one of the most prominent international research groups in the topic (the ACP section).
        The ideal candidate has an MSc in Computer Science and experience in at least one of the following areas (acquired, for example, by following courses or through work on an MSc thesis): Theory of programming languages, Compilers. Concurrent and distributed systems, Logical methods in computer science, Interactive theorem provers.
    </description>
    <where>University of Southern Denmark (Odense, DK)</where>
    <when>01/05/2024</when>
    <link>https://fa-eosd-saasfaprod1.fa.ocs.oraclecloud.com/hcmUI/CandidateExperience/en/sites/CX_1001/job/1572/</link>
    <deadline>15/05/2024</deadline>
</POST>

</postsArchive>
