<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<postsArchive>

<!-- 
    Structure of an entry
<POST>
    <title>Title of the position</title>
    <number>number of available positions</number>
    <type>either "PhD",  "Postdoc", or "Tenure/Permanent"</type>
    <description>description of the position</description>
    <where>Hosting institution</where>
    <when>Date of publishing the announcement in the form "yyyy-mm-dd" (as provided by Contact Form 7)</when>
    <link>link of the official position announcement</link>
    <deadline>deadline for application in the form "yyyy-mm-dd" (as provided by Contact Form 7)</deadline>
</POST> 

    Do not remove previous posts.
    Add new post right below here.
-->


<POST>
    <title>PhD Position in Logics for Multi-Agent Systems</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>PhD</type>
    <description>
        Utrecht University invites applications for a fully funded 4-year PhD position focused on the logical modelling of accountability and responsibility in multi-agent systems. The position is part of the interdisciplinary ELSA Lab on Legal, Regulatory, and Policy Aspects of Clinical Decision Support Systems. Applicants should hold or be near completion of an MSc in Logic, Computer Science, Mathematics, Artificial Intelligence, or a related field.
    </description>
    <where>Utrecht University, Netherlands</where>
    <when>2025-06-09</when>
    <link>https://www.uu.nl/en/organisation/working-at-utrecht-university/jobs/phd-position-in-logics-for-multi-agent-systems</link>
    <deadline>2025-07-06</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>PhD Program in Mind, Brain, and Human Thought (MBHT)</title>
    <number>Multiple</number>
    <type>PhD</type>
    <description>
        The IMT School for Advanced Studies Lucca (Italy) invites applications to its interdisciplinary PhD program in Mind, Brain, and Human Thought (MBHT), offered entirely in English. The program targets candidates with a strong background in philosophy of science, formal epistemology, or logic, and interests at the interface of philosophy, cognitive (neuro)science, and behavioral economics. The position includes a 3-year scholarship, research funds, free accommodation and meals, international mobility support, and more. PhD students will join the MInD (Models, Inferences, and Decisions) group within the MoMiLab unit.
    </description>
    <where>IMT School for Advanced Studies Lucca, Italy</where>
    <when>2025-06-04</when>
    <link>https://mbht.imtlucca.it/mbhtimt-school</link>
    <deadline>2025-06-30</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>Postdoctoral Position on Type Systems for Physical Consistency in Programming</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>Postdoc</type>
    <description>
        The LAMA (Laboratoire de Mathématiques, Université Savoie Mont Blanc) is offering a full-time, 18-month postdoctoral position starting in September 2025. The project addresses the lack of physical consistency checks in numerical simulation programs, aiming to develop a conceptually clear yet comprehensive type system solution. The postdoc will work with Tom Hirschowitz, Pierre Hyvernat, and Vincent Reverdy. Relevant skills include type theory, proof assistants, category theory, and programming language implementation, though expertise in all is not required.
    </description>
    <where>LAMA, Université Savoie Mont Blanc, France</where>
    <when>2025-06-04</when>
    <link>https://www.univ-smb.fr/wp-content/uploads/2025/06/offre-emploi-post-doct_2025_lama-shine-guli2-vf.pdf</link>
    <deadline>2025-07-03</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>10 PhD positions in Mathematics (Turin, Italy), deadline June 16th (Torino)</title>
    <number>10</number>
    <type>PhD</type>
    <description>
        The University of Turin invites applications for its PhD program in Mathematics. Research areas of interest include set theory, model theory, and descriptive set theory.
        
        There are 10 positions with scholarship, with one reserved for candidates with a foreign master degree. See the link https://www.dottorato.unito.it/do/documenti.pl/ShowFile?_id=strh;field=file;key=buoNnh487IWtnOeSOQoh8DBHAib6NEw6BMDoOqd10s9aPZTNVwd7g;t=5580 for a description of the 10 positions, some of which involve a joint supervision with a foreign partner.
        
        The interviews for the selection of candidates will take place in July, and can be carried out online. The outcome of the selection will be published at the beginning of August; admitted candidates have 7 days to accept the position.
        
        Candidates can obtain their Master degree by October 31st, 2025 (and not by the expiry date of the call).
        
        The starting date of the PhD program is November 1st, 2025.
    </description>
    <where>Dipartimento di Matematica "G. Peano", Università degli Studi di Torino</where>
    <when>2025-05-28</when>
    <link>https://www.dottorato.unito.it/do/home.pl/View?doc=Bando_XLI_ciclo.html</link>
    <deadline>2025-06-16</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>PhD Positions in the Project "Cyclic Structures in Programs and Proofs"</title>
    <number>6</number>
    <type>PhD</type>
    <description>
        We invite applications for six fully funded PhD positions (4 years) as part of the €3 million NWO-funded project "Cyclic Structures in Programs and Proofs - New Harmonies in Software Correctness by Construction". The project explores foundational aspects of software verification, including modal logic, proof theory, coalgebras, programming languages, concurrency, type systems, and proof assistants (Agda, Rocq). The research consortium involves eight Dutch and European universities. Successful candidates will be employed at one of the participating universities and collaborate across institutions.
    </description>
    <where>Various Dutch Universities (University of Groningen, Leiden University, TU Delft, etc.)</where>
    <when>2025-06-04</when>
    <link>https://cyclic-structures.gitlab.io/vacancies</link>
    <deadline>2025-05-26</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>PhD Positions in the Cluster of Excellence “Bilateral AI” at TU Wien</title>
    <number>2</number>
    <type>PhD</type>
    <description>
        The Vienna Center for Logic and Algorithms (VCLA) at TU Wien invites applications for two PhD positions within the Cluster of Excellence “Bilateral AI”. The research focuses on combining symbolic and sub-symbolic AI methods. Successful candidates will conduct research at TU Wien in collaboration with partner institutes including Johannes Kepler University Linz, AAU Klagenfurt, ISTA, TU Graz, and WU Vienna. The program offers interdisciplinary training, joint seminars, scientific workshops, and opportunities for teaching and supervision.
    </description>
    <where>Vienna Center for Logic and Algorithms (VCLA), TU Wien, Austria</where>
    <when>2024-08-30</when>
    <link>https://www.vcla.at/2024/08/open-positions-cluster-of-excellence/</link>
    <deadline>01/08/2025</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>Postdoc Positions in the Cluster of Excellence “Bilateral AI” at TU Wien</title>
    <number>Multiple</number>
    <type>Postdoc</type>
    <description>
        The Vienna Center for Logic and Algorithms (VCLA) at TU Wien invites applications for multiple Postdoc positions within the Cluster of Excellence “Bilateral AI”. The research focuses on combining symbolic and sub-symbolic AI methods. Successful candidates will conduct research at TU Wien in collaboration with partner institutes including Johannes Kepler University Linz, AAU Klagenfurt, ISTA, TU Graz, and WU Vienna. The program offers interdisciplinary training, joint seminars, scientific workshops, and opportunities for teaching and supervision.
    </description>
    <where>Vienna Center for Logic and Algorithms (VCLA), TU Wien, Austria</where>
    <when>2024-08-30</when>
    <link>https://www.vcla.at/2024/08/open-positions-cluster-of-excellence/</link>
    <deadline>01/08/2025</deadline>
</POST>


<POST>
    <title>PhD Positions in Symbolic and Sub-symbolic AI</title>
    <number>Multiple</number>
    <type>PhD</type>
    <description>
        The LIT Artificial Intelligence Lab at Johannes Kepler University Linz invites applications for multiple PhD positions within the Cluster of Excellence “Bilateral AI”. The research focuses on combining symbolic and sub-symbolic AI methods. Successful candidates will conduct research at JKU in collaboration with partner institutes AAU Klagenfurt, ISTA, TU Graz, TU Vienna, and WU Vienna. The program offers interdisciplinary training, joint seminars, scientific workshops, and opportunities for teaching and supervision.
    </description>
    <where>Johannes Kepler University Linz, Austria</where>
    <when>2025-05-12</when>
    <link>https://www.jku.at/lit-artificial-intelligence-lab/news-events/open-positions-cluster-of-excellence/</link>
    <deadline>01/08/2025</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>Open PhD and Postdoc Positions in Bilateral AI at Graz University of Technology</title>
    <number>5</number>
    <type>PhD, Postdoc</type>
    <description>
        Graz University of Technology's Institute of Machine Learning and Neural Computation (IML) invites applications for 3 PhD positions and 2 Postdoc positions within the Cluster of Excellence "Bilateral AI". The research focuses on integrating symbolic and sub-symbolic AI methods, with opportunities to work on projects related to explainable AI, quality assurance of AI-based systems, and tractable causal reasoning. Successful candidates will collaborate with partner institutions including JKU, AAU Klagenfurt, ISTA, TU Vienna, and WU Vienna.
    </description>
    <where>Graz University of Technology, Institute of Machine Learning and Neural Computation, Graz, Austria</where>
    <when>2025-05-12</when>
    <link>https://www.tugraz.at/institute/iml/institute/open-positions/bilai-jobs</link>
    <deadline>01/08/2025</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>PhD positions in The Human Mind and its Explanations: Language, Brain, and Reasoning (HuME)</title>
    <number>11</number>
    <type>PhD</type>
    <description>The HuME PhD program, jointly offered by IUSS Pavia, Università degli Studi di Milano, and Scuola Normale Superiore di Pisa, invites applications for 11 fully funded three-year positions. The program adopts a multidisciplinary approach to human cognition, encompassing philosophy of mind, epistemology, logic, cognitive sciences, neuroscience, linguistics, and artificial intelligence. Among the positions, two are funded under the FIS2 Consolidator Grant &quot;Humanizing Mathematical Knowledge: Fallibility, Technology, Know-How&quot;, and one under the FIS2 Starting Grant &quot;Severe Uncertainty: Decisions, Evidence, and Probability&quot;. Applicants should hold a Master's degree or equivalent by October 31, 2025. The program offers an annual salary of approximately €16,243, with an additional research budget of 10% of the scholarship.</description>
    <where>IUSS Pavia, Università degli Studi di Milano, and Scuola Normale Superiore di Pisa</where>
    <when>2025-05-24</when>
    <link>https://www.iusspavia.it/en/education/doctoral-programmes/human-mind-and-its-explanations-language-brain-and-reasoning-hume/apply</link>
    <deadline>2025-06-09</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>PhD position on expressivity of imperative programs</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>PhD</type>
    <description>Leiden University's Institute of Advanced Computer Science (LIACS) invites applications for a PhD position exploring the expressivity of imperative programming languages. The research focuses on the theoretical limits of programming language semantics, particularly in relation to abstract machines and control flow constructs. The project integrates concepts from programming languages, automata theory, and process algebra, with applications in compiler optimization and decompilation.</description>
    <where>Leiden Institute of Advanced Computer Science (LIACS), Leiden University</where>
    <when>2025-05-24</when>
    <link>https://www.universiteitleiden.nl/en/vacancies/2025/q2/15703-phd-candidate-on-expressivity-of-imperative-programs</link>
    <deadline>2025-06-30</deadline>
</POST>


<POST>
    <title>Two open positions on formal methods and security protocol verification (Squirrel Prover)</title>
    <number>2</number>
    <type>PhD</type>
    <description>The Pesto team at Loria (Nancy, France) is offering two positions focused on the use of the Squirrel Prover, a theorem prover for formal verification of security protocols. Projects involve applications to e-voting systems and secure messaging protocols like Signal. Candidates with backgrounds in either cryptography or formal methods are encouraged to apply.</description>
    <where>Pesto team, Loria, Nancy</where>
    <when>2025-05-24</when>
    <link>https://charlie.jacomme.fr/positions/positions/</link>
    <deadline>2025-06-15</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>PhD position in topological data analysis and neural networks for biology</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>PhD</type>
    <description>A PhD position is available at the Institut Camille Jordan in Lyon on the topic of topological data analysis and topological neural networks in molecular and evolutionary biology. The project will be carried out in collaboration with the Laboratoire de Biométrie et Biologie Évolutive and the Laboratoire de Microbiologie, Adaptation et Pathogénie.</description>
    <where>Institut Camille Jordan, Université Lyon 1</where>
    <when>2025-05-24</when>
    <link>https://emploi.cnrs.fr/Offres/Doctorant/UMR5208-PHIMAL-002/Default.aspx</link>
    <deadline>2025-06-09</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>Postdoctoral Fellowship in Discrete Mathematics</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>Postdoc</type>
    <description>The Discrete Mathematics team at the University of Liège (Belgium) invites applications for a two-year postdoctoral fellowship. Due to supervisor limitations, a pre-selection process will take place. Interested candidates should contact Manon Stipulanti by email before June 30, 2025. Further details are available via the provided link.</description>
    <where>University of Liège</where>
    <when>2025-06-30</when>
    <link>https://www.recherche.uliege.be/cms/c_13352123/fr/ipd-stema?sc_src=email_1393745&amp;sc_lid=153962203&amp;sc_llid=2028</link>
    <deadline>2025-06-30</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>PhD Program in Mathematical and Physical Sciences</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>PhD</type>
    <description>The University of Udine invites applications for its PhD program in Mathematics and Physics, starting November 1, 2025. The program offers a three-year scholarship and travel funding. Research areas of interest in 2025 include computability theory, reverse mathematics, Weihrauch reducibility, and set theory with a focus on large cardinals. Applications close on June 20, 2025, 2 PM (Italian time). Interviews begin online July 21.</description>
    <where>University of Udine, Italy</where>
    <when>2025-06-20</when>
    <link>https://www.uniud.it/en/research/do-research/doctorate-res/ammissione/modulistica/annexes-phd-call-2025/call-for-applications_41-cycle-university-of-udine.pdf</link>
    <deadline>2025-06-20</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>PhD Position in Logic in Computer Science and Semiring Semantics</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>PhD</type>
    <description>The University of Tartu invites applications for a fully funded PhD position in the area of logic in computer science, database theory, and semiring semantics. The research focuses on extending classical logic and complexity tools to semiring-enriched models, relevant to annotated databases and provenance. The position offers international collaboration and a planned research visit to Helsinki. Applicants should hold a Master's in computer science, mathematics, or a related field.</description>
    <where>University of Tartu</where>
    <when>2025-04-30</when>
    <link>https://estonia.dreamapply.com/en_GB/courses/course/1189-phd-mathematics-and-computer-science-specialisation-computer-science</link>
    <deadline>2025-05-15</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>PhD Position in Knowledge Representation and Reasoning</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>PhD</type>
    <description>The Individual and Collective Reasoning Group (ICR) at the University of Luxembourg, led by Prof. Leon van der Torre, is seeking a PhD candidate in Knowledge Representation and Reasoning. The research will focus on areas such as formal argumentation, deontic logic, normative multiagent systems, and the integration of symbolic and non-symbolic techniques. Applicants are encouraged to consult the chapter "Thirteen Challenges of Formal and Computational Argumentation" in HOFA3. The position starts in September 2025 and includes a competitive salary, doctoral training, and support for scientific activities.</description>
    <where>University of Luxembourg</where>
    <when>2025-04-13</when>
    <link>https://recruitment.uni.lu/en/details.html?nPostingId=104056&amp;nPostingTargetId=149108&amp;id=QMUFK026203F3VBQB7V7VV4S8&amp;LG=UK&amp;languageSelect=UK&amp;sType=Social%20Recruiting&amp;mask=karriereseiten</link>
    <deadline>2025-05-15</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>PhD Position on Efficient Enumeration via Edits</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>PhD</type>
    <description>The LINKS team at Inria Lille is offering a PhD position on the topic of "Efficient enumeration via edits". The project aims to develop enumeration algorithms where solutions are described through edits from previous ones, with applications in automata theory, graph theory, and databases. The PhD will be supervised by Antoine Amarilli and Mikaël Monet within the dynamic research environment of the LINKS team, a joint effort of Inria Lille, University of Lille, and CRIStAL laboratory.</description>
    <where>Inria Lille</where>
    <when>2025-04-13</when>
    <link>https://a3nm.net/work/research/offers/phd_enumeration_changes.pdf</link>
    <deadline>2025-04-30</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>PhD Position in Combinatorics, Numeration Systems, and Automata Theory</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>PhD</type>
    <description>The Discrete Mathematics team of the Department of Mathematics at the University of Liège (ULiège) is offering a PhD position within the FNRS MIS project "An in-depth study of regular sequences as a (discrete) bridge between combinatorics on words and abstract numeration systems." The project lies at the intersection of combinatorics on words, numeration systems, number theory, and automata/formal language theory. The position is for 4 years, tentatively starting in October 2025 (with some flexibility).</description>
    <where>University of Liège</where>
    <when>2025-04-13</when>
    <link>https://euraxess.ec.europa.eu/jobs/307621</link>
    <deadline>Not specified</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>Postdoc Position in Combinatorics, Numeration Systems, and Automata Theory</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>Postdoc</type>
    <description>The Discrete Mathematics team of the Department of Mathematics at the University of Liège (ULiège) is offering a postdoctoral position within the FNRS MIS project "An in-depth study of regular sequences as a (discrete) bridge between combinatorics on words and abstract numeration systems." The research lies at the interface of combinatorics on words, numeration systems, number theory, and automata/formal language theory. The position is intended to last 1 to 3 years and is expected to start around October 2025 (with flexible starting date).</description>
    <where>University of Liège</where>
    <when>2025-04-13</when>
    <link>https://euraxess.ec.europa.eu/jobs/307628</link>
    <deadline>Not specified</deadline>
</POST>


<POST>
    <title>Postdoc in Model Theory of Analytic Functions</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>Postdoc</type>
    <description>A 6-month postdoctoral position is available at the University of Leeds, funded by the EPSRC grant "Model theory of analytic functions". The position is intended for early-career researchers with aligned interests. Interested candidates can contact Vincenzo Mantova for more information.</description>
    <where>University of Leeds</where>
    <when>2025-04-13</when>
    <link>https://jobs.leeds.ac.uk/Vacancy.aspx?ref=EPSMA1124</link>
    <deadline>2025-04-27</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>Assistant Professor in Mathematical Logic (Tenure Track)</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>Tenure/Permanent</type>
    <description>Stockholm University's Department of Mathematics is hiring an Assistant Professor in Mathematics with a focus on Mathematical Logic. Applicants from all areas of logic are welcome. The department hosts a vibrant logic group and encourages applications from underrepresented groups. The position is tenure-track and includes involvement in the department's regular seminars and collaborations.</description>
    <where>Stockholm University</where>
    <when>2025-04-13</when>
    <link>https://su.varbi.com/en/what:job/jobID:796743/where:4/</link>
    <deadline>2025-04-15</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>PhD Fellowship in Higher-Order Metaphysics</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>PhD</type>
    <description>The Department of Philosophy at the University of Geneva is offering a four-year PhD fellowship as part of Fabrice Correia's SNSF project "Higher-Order Metaphysics: Foundations, Motivations and Hyperintensional Developments". The project is associated with the eidos Centre for Metaphysics and aims to address foundational and hyperintensional aspects of higher-order metaphysics. Applicants should have a good command of English; knowledge of French is not required.</description>
    <where>University of Geneva</where>
    <when>2025-04-13</when>
    <link>https://eidoscentre.org/</link>
    <deadline>2025-05-15</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>Postdoc Position in Semantics of Programming Languages</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>Postdoc</type>
    <description>A postdoctoral position is available in the Plume team at LIP, ENS de Lyon, focusing on the semantics of programming languages. Topics of interest include probabilistic programming, differentiable programming, linear logic, and denotational semantics. Candidates with backgrounds in functional programming, lambda calculus, types, or Curry-Howard correspondence are encouraged to apply.</description>
    <where>ENS de Lyon</where>
    <when>2025-04-02</when>
    <link>https://www.ens-lyon.fr/LIP/PLUME/</link>
    <deadline>2025-05-31</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>Postdoc Position in Computational Models and Discrete Dynamical Systems</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>Postdoc</type>
    <description>The ANR project ALARICE is offering a postdoctoral position at the interface of computational models, discrete dynamical systems, algorithmic complexity, finite-model theory, and graph logics. Candidates with expertise in at least two of these areas are encouraged to apply. The researcher will join the Natural Computing group at LIS in Marseille Luminy.</description>
    <where>LIS, Marseille Luminy</where>
    <when>2025-02-04</when>
    <link>https://alarice.lis-lab.fr/</link>
    <deadline>2025-06-01</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>PhD Positions in Mathematical Logic</title>
    <number>2-3</number>
    <type>PhD</type>
    <description>PhD and Postdoc positions available in the Mathematical Logic Group at the University of Würzburg, focusing on ordinal analysis, reverse mathematics, and related fields.</description>
    <where>University of Würzburg (DE)</where>
    <when>2025-03-20</when>
    <link>https://prooftheory.blog/2020/06/03/from-cut-elimination-to-reverse-mathematics/</link>
    <deadline>2025-04-25</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>Postdoc Positions in Mathematical Logic</title>
    <number>2-3</number>
    <type>Postdoc</type>
    <description>PhD and Postdoc positions available in the Mathematical Logic Group at the University of Würzburg, focusing on ordinal analysis, reverse mathematics, and related fields.</description>
    <where>University of Würzburg (DE)</where>
    <when>2025-03-20</when>
    <link>https://prooftheory.blog/2020/06/03/from-cut-elimination-to-reverse-mathematics/</link>
    <deadline>2025-04-25</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>PhD Positions in Foundations of Neuro-Symbolic Multi-Agent Systems</title>
    <number>2</number>
    <type>PhD</type>
    <description>The University of Sussex is offering two PhD positions in Computer Science, focusing on the foundations of Neuro-Symbolic Multi-Agent Systems, including logic, game theory, and formal methods. The studentship includes a tax-free stipend, fee waiver, and research grant.</description>
    <where>University of Sussex, UK</where>
    <when>2025-03-20</when>
    <link>https://www.sussex.ac.uk/study/fees-funding/phd-funding/view/1839-PhD-Informatics-Studentship:-Foundations-of-Neuro-Symbolic-Multi-Agent-Systems</link>
    <deadline>2025-04-25</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>PhD Position on Formal Methods for the Safety of AI</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>PhD</type>
    <description>The Laboratoire d'Informatique de l'École Polytechnique (LIX) is offering a PhD position in the Cosynus team, focusing on the verification of probabilistic properties for AI. The research will explore formal methods for AI safety, including robustness, explainability, and imprecise probability models.</description>
    <where>École Polytechnique, Institut Polytechnique de Paris, France</where>
    <when>2025-10-01</when>
    <link>mailto:sylvie.putot@polytechnique.edu,eric.goubault@polytechnique.edu</link>
    <deadline>2025-06-25</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>Postdoctoral Researcher in Programming Languages</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>Postdoc</type>
    <description>The University of Bristol invites applications for a postdoctoral researcher in Programming Languages. The successful candidate will have the freedom to pursue self-directed research in areas such as functional programming, program verification/analysis, program synthesis, and type theory. The position is for 18 months, with the possibility of extension.</description>
    <where>University of Bristol</where>
    <when>2025-03-26</when>
    <link>https://www.bristol.ac.uk/jobs/find/details/?jobId=372879&amp;jobTitle=Senior%20Research%20Associate%20in%20Programming%20Languages</link>
    <deadline>2025-03-26</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>Faculty Positions in Computer Science at École Polytechnique</title>
    <number>8</number>
    <type>Tenure/Permanent</type>
    <description>École Polytechnique, a leading engineering school within IP Paris, invites applications for multiple faculty positions in Computer Science starting in September 2025. Openings include positions in cybersecurity, trustworthy AI, optimization, reinforcement learning, and multimodal AI.</description>
    <where>École Polytechnique, France</where>
    <when>2025-09-01</when>
    <link>https://candidatures-calliope.polytechnique.fr/calliope-fo/recherche/index.php?lang=fr</link>
    <deadline>2025-04-04</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>Postdoctoral Positions in TRUST and DEZINFO Projects</title>
    <number>3</number>
    <type>Postdoc</type>
    <description>The Institute of Computer Science of the Czech Academy of Sciences (ICS CAS) invites applications for three postdoctoral positions in the TRUST and DEZINFO projects, focusing on theoretical computer science within the LogICS group.</description>
    <where>Institute of Computer Science, Czech Academy of Sciences</where>
    <when>2025-02-03</when>
    <link>http://www.cs.cas.cz/logics/</link>
    <deadline>2025-03-31</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>PhD Positions in Proof Logging and Combinatorial Optimization</title>
    <number>2</number>
    <type>PhD</type>
    <description>Two PhD positions are available in Bart Bogaerts' research group at KU Leuven, focusing on proof logging and explanations for combinatorial optimization.</description>
    <where>KU Leuven</where>
    <when>2025-02-03</when>
    <link>https://www.kuleuven.be/personeel/jobsite/jobs/60425822</link>
    <deadline>2025-02-06</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>Postdoc Position in Combinatorial Optimization and Proof Logging</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>Postdoc</type>
    <description>A postdoc position is available in Bart Bogaerts' research group at KU Leuven, focusing on advanced research in combinatorial optimization and proof logging.</description>
    <where>KU Leuven</where>
    <when>2025-02-03</when>
    <link>https://www.kuleuven.be/personeel/jobsite/jobs/60411819</link>
    <deadline>2025-02-06</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>ATER Positions in Computer Science</title>
    <number>3</number>
    <type>Postdoc</type>
    <description>The Department of Computer Science at ENS de Lyon is offering 3 ATER positions for the 2025–2026 academic year. Responsibilities include teaching practical and theoretical classes at undergraduate and graduate levels. Research topics cover all areas of the Laboratoire de l'Informatique du Parallélisme (LIP).</description>
    <where>ENS de Lyon, Department of Computer Science</where>
    <when>2025-02-03</when>
    <link>https://www.ens-lyon.fr/lecole/travailler-lens-de-lyon/recrutement-des-enseignants-et-des-chercheurs/recrutement-dater</link>
    <deadline>2025-02-17</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>Assistant Professor Positions in Computer Science (Warsaw, PL)</title>
    <number>7</number>
    <type>Tenure/Permanent</type>
    <description>The Faculty of Mathematics, Informatics, and Mechanics at the University of Warsaw invites applications for 7 assistant professor positions in computer science. Research areas include algorithms, logic and automata, computational biology, distributed systems, programming languages, cryptography, databases, and machine learning.</description>
    <where>University of Warsaw, Faculty of Mathematics, Informatics, and Mechanics</where>
    <when>2025-02-03</when>
    <link>https://www.mimuw.edu.pl/en/open-positions</link>
    <deadline>2025-02-14</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>Visiting Assistant Professor at the University of Denver</title>
    <type>Postdoc</type>
    <description>The Department of Mathematics at the University of Denver invites applications for three Visiting Assistant Professor positions in mathematics to begin on Sept 1, 2025. These are non-tenure-track positions that may be renewed for a maximum of three years. 
    </description>
    <where>University of Denver, Colorado, USA</where>
    <deadline>2025-05-31</deadline>
    <link>https://www.mathjobs.org/jobs/list/26215</link>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>Fully-Funded PhD Studentships in Programming Languages and Systems</title>
    <type>PhD</type>
    <description>The Programming Languages and Systems (PLAS) group at the University of Kent invites applications for 3.5-year fully-funded PhD scholarships, available for both UK and international students. Topics span from concurrency, formal verification, and cost analysis to programming language theory and type systems. Scholars also benefit from teacher training and diverse housing options on a scenic campus near Canterbury. Applications are due 15 February 2025.</description>
    <where>University of Kent, Canterbury, UK</where>
    <deadline>2025-02-15</deadline>
    <link>https://www.kent.ac.uk/courses/postgraduate/283/computer-science</link>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>PhD Position in Knowledge Representation and Reasoning</title>
    <type>PhD</type>
    <description>The Individual and Collective Reasoning Group (ICR), led by Prof. Leon van der Torre, at the University of Luxembourg, is seeking a PhD candidate in Knowledge Representation and Reasoning. Areas of interest include formal argumentation, deontic logic, normative multiagent systems, and integration of non-symbolic and symbolic techniques. Applicants should refer to the chapter "Thirteen Challenges of Formal and Computational Argumentation" from the Handbook of Formal Argumentation (available online) to prepare their research proposal.</description>
    <where>University of Luxembourg, Belval Campus</where>
    <deadline>2025-01-31</deadline>
    <link>https://wwwen.uni.lu/jobs</link>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>Un assegno di ricerca (12) mesi Progetto eDefAI - Università del Salento (Lecce)</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>Postdoc</type>
    <description>
        Posizione aperta per assegno di ricerca di tipo B per 12 mesi sul Progetto eDefAI (Ethical Design for AI) PNRR FAIR Spoke 6  presso l' Università degli studi del Salento (Lecce).  PI: Paolo Baldi

La ricerca sarà concentrata su applicazioni di logiche per la formalizzazione di norme etiche e epistemiche per il ragionamento con dati in AI.  E' richiesta specializzazione in logiche non-classiche, preferibilmente argomentazione formale e logica deontica.
    </description>
    <where>Centro Digital Humanities - Dipartimento di Studi Umanistici</where>
    <when>2025-01-06</when>
    <link>https://www1.unisalento.it/bandi-concorsi/-/bandi/view/67531561</link>
    <deadline>2025-01-20</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>Post-Doc Position at Roma Tre (Rome, Italy)</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>Postdoc</type>
    <description>
        We are pleased to announce a research fellow position opportunity at Roma Tre University under the project:

Project Title: "Logical Methods and Formal Verification of Post-Quantum Cryptographic Algorithms"

Funding Source: Laboratory of Cryptography and Cybersecurity
Duration: One year (with the possibility of extension for an additional year)
Application Deadline: January 10, 2025
Research Areas: Cryptography, Algebra, Computer Science, Mathematical Logic.
Bando di concorso Rep. 24_Prot. 2068/2024 (https://bit.ly/3BDCCo2)

https://matematicafisica.uniroma3.it/dipartimento/bandi-e-concorsi/bandi-per-assegni-di-ricerca/

Contact person:
Prof. Marco Pedicini
Department of Mathematics and Physics
Roma Tre University
Via della Vasca Navale 84 I-00146 Roma (Italy)
Email: marco.pedicini@uniroma3.it
Website: http://www.mat.uniroma3.it/users/pedicini

Roma Tre University encourages applications from candidates of all backgrounds. Don't miss this opportunity to contribute to cutting-edge research in the field of cryptography.
    </description>
    <where>Department of Mathematics and Physics, Roma Tre University</where>
    <when>2024-12-24</when>
    <link>https://matematicafisica.uniroma3.it/dipartimento/bandi-e-concorsi/bandi-per-assegni-di-ricerca/</link>
    <deadline>2025-01-10</deadline>
</POST>


<POST>
    <title>PhD Fellowships in MathPhDInFrance Program</title>
    <number>25</number>
    <type>PhD</type>
    <description>The MathPhDInFrance program offers 25 PhD fellowships for projects co-directed by laboratories in Île-de-France and other French regions. Doctoral studies commence in fall 2025. Eligibility: candidates must not have spent more than one year in France between February 14, 2022, and February 14, 2025.</description>
    <where>Île-de-France and other French regions</where>
    <when>2024-12-17</when>
    <link>https://mathphdinfrance.fr/</link>
    <deadline>2025-02-14</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>PhD Positions at the University of Copenhagen</title>
    <number>Multiple</number>
    <type>PhD</type>
    <description>The University of Copenhagen invites applications for PhD positions with a tentative start date of 1 September 2025 (negotiable). Research areas include algorithms, complexity theory, and related fields. Students will join a world-class research environment, ranked 1st in the EU for algorithms and complexity, and affiliated with the Basic Algorithms Research Copenhagen (BARC) centre.</description>
    <where>University of Copenhagen, Denmark</where>
    <when>2024-12-16</when>
    <link>https://employment.ku.dk/phd/?show=163037</link>
    <deadline>2025-01-10</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>Postdoctoral Positions at the University of Copenhagen</title>
    <number>Multiple</number>
    <type>Postdoc</type>
    <description>The University of Copenhagen announces postdoctoral positions with a flexible starting date between April and September 2025. Research areas include algorithms, complexity theory, and foundational breakthroughs using mathematics. Join a leading environment ranked 1st in the EU, home to the BARC centre and active at top-tier conferences like STOC, FOCS, and SODA.</description>
    <where>University of Copenhagen, Denmark</where>
    <when>2024-12-16</when>
    <link>https://jobportal.ku.dk/videnskabelige-stillinger/?show=163121</link>
    <deadline>2025-01-10</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>PhD in Proof-Theoretic Semantics for Non-Classical and Modal Logics (London, UK)</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>PhD</type>
    <description>We invite applications for a four-year PhD studentship on the Leverhulme-funded project "ECUMENICAL: Proof-theoretic semantics for non-classical and modal logics", led by Dr. Elaine Pimentel, Prof. David Pym, and Prof. Luiz Carlos Pereira at UCL. This interdisciplinary studentship, situated at the intersection of informatics, mathematics, and philosophy, focuses on developing proof-theoretic semantics for non-classical and modal logics, constructing the necessary abstract mathematical meta-theory, and investigating the implications of inferentialist semantics for systems verification. The successful candidate will work within the Programming Principles, Logic, and Verification group at UCL.
    Application deadlines:
    3 February 2025 (for a May 2025 start)
    1 July 2025 (for an October 2025 start)</description>
    <where>UCL Computer Science</where>
    <when>2024-11-29</when>
    <link>https://www.findaphd.com/phds/project/ecumenical-proof-theoretic-semantics-for-non-classical-and-modal-logics/?p177226</link>
    <deadline>2025-07-01</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>PostDoc Position in Proof Logging for Combinatorial Optimization (Leuven, the Netherlands)</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>Postdoc</type>
    <description>Prof. Bart Bogaerts is looking for talented PostDocs to join the CertiFOX project, where we bring 100% correctness guarantees to tools for combinatorial optimization. For more information, see the CertiFOX project page or contact Bart Bogaerts at bart.bogaerts@kuleuven.be .</description>
    <where>Leuven, the Netherlands</where>
    <when>2024-11-29</when>
    <link>https://www.bartbogaerts.eu/projects/CertiFOX/#Hiring</link>
    <deadline>2025-02-06</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>Senior Lecturer Position in Mathematically Structured Programming @ Strathclyde (Glasgow, Scotland)</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>Tenure/Permanent</type>
    <description>The Department of Computer and Information Sciences at the University of Strathclyde in Glasgow seeks to appoint a Chancellor's Fellow in Mathematically Structured Programming. We welcome applications from candidates with expertise in a range of topics in the mathematical foundations of computer sciences and applications, such as: 
        * Logic, including modal and temporal logic, model checking, and proof theory;
        * Category theory, including categorical semantics, and applied category theory;
        * Type theory and functional programming, including semantics, metatheory, and implementation;
        * Formal and mechanised mathematics, including certified programming and the use and implementation of proof assistants.
    For more information, see the job page or contact Fredrik Nordvall Forsberg at fredrik.nordvall-forsberg@strath.ac.uk, or Clemens Kupke at clemens.kupke@strath.ac.uk.</description>
    <where>University of Strathclyde, Glasgow, Scotland</where>
    <when>2024-11-29</when>
    <link>https://www.jobs.ac.uk/job/DKR108/strathclyde-chancellors-fellow-in-mathematically-structured-programming</link>
    <deadline>2025-01-05</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>Assistant Professor (Tenure Track) in Theoretical Computer Science at ETH (Zurich, Switzerland)</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>Tenure/Permanent</type>
    <description>The Department of Computer Science at ETH Zurich invites applications for an assistant professorship (tenure track) in theoretical computer science, focusing on areas such as automated and interactive theorem proving, logic, SAT, SMT, semantics, and related topics. The position is open for applications until January 15th, 2025.</description>
    <where>ETH Zurich, Switzerland</where>
    <when>2024-11-29</when>
    <link>https://www.ethz.ch/en/the-department.html</link>
    <deadline>2025-01-15</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>Postdoc &amp; Senior Researcher Positions at Hasuo Laboratory (Tokyo, Japan)</title>
    <number>Multiple</number>
    <type>Postdoc</type>
    <description>Hasuo Laboratory at the National Institute of Informatics, Tokyo, Japan invites applications for positions in areas such as abstract and concrete automated verification, and mathematical logic for software, systems, and society. Collaboration opportunities include working with Bart Jacobs, Joost-Pieter Katoen, and Sam Staton. Positions last up to 4.5 years. Contact Ichiro Hasuo for more information.</description>
    <where>Hasuo Laboratory, National Institute of Informatics, Tokyo, Japan</where>
    <when>2024-11-29</when>
    <link>https://www.nii.ac.jp/en</link>
    <deadline>2025-02-28</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>PhD Positions at Hasuo Laboratory (Tokyo, Japan)</title>
    <number>Multiple</number>
    <type>PhD</type>
    <description>Hasuo Laboratory at the National Institute of Informatics, Tokyo, Japan invites applications for positions in areas such as abstract and concrete automated verification, and mathematical logic for software, systems, and society. Collaboration opportunities include working with Bart Jacobs, Joost-Pieter Katoen, and Sam Staton. Positions last up to 4.5 years. Contact Ichiro Hasuo for more information.</description>
    <where>Hasuo Laboratory, National Institute of Informatics, Tokyo, Japan</where>
    <when>2024-11-29</when>
    <link>https://www.nii.ac.jp/en</link>
    <deadline>2025-02-28</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>Two 2-Year Postdoc Positions at LIP (Lyon, France)</title>
    <number>2</number>
    <type>Postdoc</type>
    <description>Two two-year postdoc positions, offered by the Labex MiLyon, have been opened in Lyon, France. All research topics of the LIP (the computer science lab at ENS de Lyon) are eligible: algorithms, graph theory, statistical learning, computer arithmetic, computer algebra, high-performance computing, combinatorics, compilation, algorithmic complexity, cryptography, distributed computing, quantum computing, programming languages, logic, computational models, parallelism, formal proofs, scheduling, networks, semantics, and verification. Candidates must find a mentor in the lab prior to their official application. Postdoc positions with no teaching duty, for the period September 2025 to August 2027. Contact at LIP: Isabelle Guérin Lassous, director of LIP (isabelle.guerin-lassous@ens-lyon.fr).
    </description>
    <where>LIP, ENS de Lyon, Lyon, France</where>
    <when>2024-11-29</when>
    <link>https://milyon.universite-lyon.fr/postdoctoral-positions-2025-2027-351922.kjsp</link>
    <deadline>2025-01-10</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>18-Month Full-Time Postdoc Position at LAMA (Chamberí, France)</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>Postdoc</type>
    <description>The LAMA (Laboratoire de Mathématiques) offers an 18-month full-time postdoc position starting in February 2025. The aim of the position is to develop a conceptually clear solution for verifying the physical coherence of numerical simulations, addressing limitations of current programming language type systems. The successful candidate will work with Tom Hirschowitz and Pierre Hyvernat (Mathematics Laboratory) and Vincent Reverdy (Annecy Laboratory of Particle Physics). Relevant skills include type theory, category theory, programming language theory, proof assistants, and language implementation, though mastery of all is not required.</description>
    <where>LAMA, Université Savoie Mont Blanc</where>
    <when>2024-11-19</when>
    <link>https://univ-smb.nous-recrutons.fr/poste/nzyn17a55c-chercheur-post-doctorant-fh-usmb-shine-guli-anr-22-exes-0017/</link>
    <deadline>2024-12-09</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>1-year Part-Time Postdoc Position in Logic, Semantics, or Philosophy of Language (Vienna, Austria)</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>Postdoc</type>
    <description>A 1-year part-time (70%) postdoc position in logic, semantics, philosophy of language, or similar research areas. The position is funded by the project MODREQUAM (&quot;Modal Reasoning, Quarc and Metaphysics&quot;, 2024-2028) at the Department of Philosophy, Central European University, Vienna. For further information, please contact Matteo Pascucci at pascuccim@ceu.edu.</description>
    <where>Central European University, Department of Philosophy, Vienna</where>
    <when>2024-11-19</when>
    <link>https://careers.ceu.edu/job/Vienna-Post-doctoral-Researcher-%28fmd%29-1100/1136676555/</link>
    <deadline>2024-12-31</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>2-year Research Assistant Position in Logic (Bologna, Italy)</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>Postdoc</type>
    <description>A 2-year research assistant position (renewable up to 5 years) in logic at the Department of Mathematics at the University of Bologna, funded by the ERC grant &quot;Definable Algebraic Topology&quot;. Holding a PhD is not a necessary eligibility requirement; a master's degree is sufficient.</description>
    <where>University of Bologna, Department of Mathematics</where>
    <when>2024-11-19</when>
    <link>https://bandi.unibo.it/ricerca/assegni-ricerca?id_bando=68580</link>
    <deadline>2024-11-30</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>Postdoctoral fellow/junior scientist in proof theory and algebraic logic (Prague, Czech Republic)</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>Postdoc</type>
    <description>We seek a postdoctoral fellow or junior scientist to join the Czech Science Foundation project “Interpolation, Amalgamation, and Computation” (INTERACT), led by Dr. Wesley Fussner at the Institute of Computer Science of the Czech Academy of Sciences. The project aims to develop an encompassing theory of interpolation across varied logical environments by unifying proof-theoretic and algebraic approaches. The successful candidate will conduct research along this theme, both individually and in collaboration with the PI and other team members. More information on the project may be found on its webpage (http://www.wesleyfussner.com/interact.html).</description>
    <where>Institute of Computer Science of the Czech Academy of Sciences</where>
    <when>2024-11-15</when>
    <link>https://www.cs.cas.cz/job-offer/Postdoctoral-fellow-junior-scientist-Fussner-2024/en</link>
    <deadline>2025-01-15</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>PhD candidate in algebraic logic (Prague, Czech Republic)</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>PhD</type>
    <description>We seek a Ph.D. candidate to join the Czech Science Foundation project “Interpolation, Amalgamation, and Computation” (INTERACT), led by Dr. Wesley Fussner at the Institute of Computer Science of the Czech Academy of Sciences. The project aims to develop an encompassing theory of interpolation across varied logical environments by unifying proof-theoretic and algebraic approaches. The successful candidate will conduct research on the themes of the project, working toward a Ph.D. dissertation under the supervision of Dr. Wesley Fussner. More information on the project may be found on the INTERACT webpage (http://www.wesleyfussner.com/interact.html).</description>
    <where>Institute of Computer Science of the Czech Academy of Sciences</where>
    <when>2024-11-15</when>
    <link>https://www.cs.cas.cz/job-offer/PhD-candidate-algebraic-logic-Fussner-2024/en</link>
    <deadline>2025-02-15</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>PhD in Theoretical Computer Science (Birmingham, UK)</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>PhD</type>
    <description>We invite applications for PhD study at the University of Birmingham.  
    We are a group of (mostly) theoretical computer scientists who explore fundamental concepts in computation. Our work includes category theory, computational complexity, programming language semantics, proof theory, type theory, verification and much else besides. 
    See our webpage, with links to individual researchers, here: https://www.birmingham.ac.uk/research/activity/computer-science/theory-of-computation/index.aspx</description>
    <where>University of Birmingham</where>
    <when>2024-11-07</when>
    <link>https://www.birmingham.ac.uk/schools/computer-science/postgraduate-research/applying-for-phd-in-computer-science</link>
    <deadline>2025-03-07</deadline>
</POST> 

<POST>
    <title>Associate Professor in Computational Linguistics (London, UK)</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>Tenure/Permanent</type>
    <description>UCL's department of Language Sciences and Linguistics  is advertising a new position in Computational Linguistics. Here is the link for more information and to apply.
    </description>
    <where>University College London</where>
    <when>2024-11-07</when>
    <link>https://www.ucl.ac.uk/work-at-ucl/search-ucl-jobs/details?nPostingId=11512&amp;nPostingTargetId=28204</link>
    <deadline>2024-12-31</deadline>
</POST> 

<POST>
    <title>Postdoc in Type Theory/Logic</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>Postdoc</type>
    <description>We have a postdoc position open in type theory and mathematical logic.  Type theory is the core of the grant project it's attached to, but applicants working on related topics in logic are also very welcome.
    </description>
    <where>Stockholm University</where>
    <when>2024-10-27</when>
    <link>https://www.su.se/english/about-the-university/work-at-su/available-jobs?rmpage=job&amp;rmjob=24395&amp;rmlang=UK </link>
    <deadline>2024-11-04</deadline>
</POST> 

<POST>
    <title>Postdocs in  Foundations of Computer Science</title>
    <number>10</number>
    <type>Postdoc</type>
    <description>IRIF (CNRS and Université de Paris), Paris, France, is seeking excellent candidates for postdoctoral positions in all areas of the Foundations of Computer Science. Every year, 5-10 new postdocs join IRIF.

IRIF (Institute for Research in Foundations of Computer Science) is a joint laboratory of the CNRS (French National Center for Scientific Research) and Université Paris Cité. Currently, it hosts about 90 permanent faculty members, 40 non-permanent full-time researchers, and 50 Ph.D. students. For further information about IRIF please see https://www.irif.fr/en/informations/presentation .

The postdoc positions at IRIF are financed either by the laboratory resources, or by group or personal grants, or by joint applications of IRIF members and the candidate to outside funding agencies with which IRIF is affiliated.

The starting date of the positions is usually in September-October, but this may sometimes vary. Candidates must hold a Ph.D. degree in Computer Science or a related area before the starting date of the position. Knowledge of French is not required, and applications can be sent either in French or in English.
    </description>
    <where>IRIF (Université Paris Cité)</where>
    <when>2024-10-08</when>
    <link>https://www.irif.fr/postes/postdoc </link>
    <deadline>2024-11-10</deadline>
</POST> 

<POST>
    <title>Tenure track position (Assistant Professor, Associate Professor or Professor) in Discrete Mathematics</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>Tenure/Permanent</type>
    <description>
        Mathematics education and research at Tampere University are hosted by the Computing Sciences unit and the Faculty of Information Technology and Communications. We conduct strong research in the areas of mathematics including

        Applications of algebraic topology
        Inverse problems
        Mathematical logic
        Mathematical systems theory and functional analysis
        Our personnel consists of 5 professors, 15 lecturers/instructors, and roughly 30 research staff members including post-doctoral researchers and doctoral students. To complement and strengthen our research profile, we invite applications for an Assistant/Associate/Full Professor in Discrete Mathematics (Tenure Track). We are especially seeking candidates with an excellent track record in the area of mathematical logic. Expertise on applications is considered an additional strength.

        The successful candidate is expected to lead world-class scientific research and to demonstrate their potential in securing substantial research funding. They will also participate in teaching and supervision of students in the area of mathematical logic.  We are seeking an active member to our academic community and value potential for local research collaboration. The more detailed tenure-track objectives will be set based on the level and previous experience of the candidate.
    </description>
    <where>Tampere Univesity (FIN)</where>
    <when>2024-09-16</when>
    <link>https://tuni.rekrytointi.com/paikat/?o=A_RJ&amp;jgid=3&amp;jid=2359</link>
    <deadline>2024-09-30</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>PhD Position at TU Vienna, AXAIS project</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>PhD</type>
    <description>
        The research group Theory and Logic , Institute of Logic and Computation of TU Wien (the Vienna University of Technology) is looking for an exceptionally talented and motivated student for a PhD position.

        The 4-year position (30 hrs/week) is embedded in the AXAIS project (“Acquiring and explaining norms for AI systems”) funded by the Vienna Science and Technology Fund . This interdisciplinary project, involving TU Wien (PI: Agata Ciabattoni ), the University of Maryland (PI: John Horty ), and the AIT - Austrian Institute of Technology (PI: Cristinel Mateis), will start December 2024.
    </description>
    <where>TU Wien (A)</where>
    <when>2024-09-16</when>
    <link>https://www.vcla.at/2024/08/phd-position-at-tu-wien-axais-project/</link>
    <deadline>2024-10-01</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>Assistant Professorship (W2tt) for Pure Mathematics</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>Tenure/Permanent</type>
    <description>
        The Department of Mathematics at Technical University of Darmstadt is renowned for its excellent research and teaching. With a strong commitment to innovation and the values of TU Darmstadt, the department covers a wide range of mathematical disciplines, including pure, applied, and computer-oriented mathematics. Our faculty members are internationally recognized in their respective fields and promote a modern inclusive research community. We maintain strong interdisciplinary and international collaborations, as well as collaborations within the context of the Rhine-Main Universities (RMU). With the advertised professorship, we aim to strengthen and expand our efforts in this regard.

        As part of its commitment to the interdisciplinary environment of TU Darmstadt, the department provides service-teaching for other technical departments. Particularly relevant for the advertised professorship is that the education of students in the formal foundations of computer science is provided by the Department of Mathematics.

        The Department of Mathematics at TU Darmstadt seeks candidates at the earliest possible date (no later than October 2025) for an assistant professorship (W2 with tenure track) for Pure Mathematics.

        The research focus of the professorship should be in one of the areas:

        Discrete algorithmic mathematics,
        Logic with connections to theoretical computer science, or
        Graph theory/combinatorics.

        The department places great value on engagement in teaching within the mathematics programs and mathematical education for students of other departments. Therefore, the professorship should also contribute to teaching with a high level of commitment by participating in the mathematics programs and lectures on formal foundations of computer science.

        Furthermore, participation in the department's third-party funding efforts in the RMU context (particularly relating to the DAIS initiative https://dais.rhein-main-universitaeten.de/) is expected.

        If you have any questions about this position, please contact Prof. Dr. rer. nat. Pascal Schweitzer via email at schweitzer@mathematik.tu-darmstadt.de.
    </description>
    <where>TU Darmstadt (DE)</where>
    <when>2024-09-16</when>
    <link>https://www.career.tu-darmstadt.de/HPv3.Jobs/TU-Darmstadt/stellenangebot/38926/48871?lang=en</link>
    <deadline>2024-10-01</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>Teaching position for logic courses at the Université de Fribourg</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>Tenure/Permanent</type>
    <description>
        The Université de Fribourg (Switzerland) is looking to fill the position of a lecturer (m/f/d) in logic (2 SWS per semester) starting in the fall semester of 2025.

        Requirements:
        - Doctorate in philosophy (preferably in logic, e.g. formal logic, history of logic, argumentation theory).
        - Teaching experience in logic and argumentation theory at a philosophy institute (formal logic, history of logic, philosophical logic, applied logic).
        - Very good knowledge of French and German.

        Tasks:
        - Teaching the compulsory introductory course in formal logic alternately in German and French (2 hours per week, each in the fall semester).
        - Teaching the bilingual elective subject “Outils formels en philosophie/Formal Tools in Philosophy” each in the spring semester (2 SWS).

        Start of activity:
        September 1, 2025

        Applications received by October 31, 2024 will be fully considered.

        Applications should include:
        1. CV,
        2. letter of motivation with details of relevant teaching experience,
        3. a writing sample of approximately 15-20 pages.
        Applications should be submitted by email to: beatrice.lienemann@unifr.ch

        A confidential letter of recommendation should also be sent by email to the following address : beatrice.lienemann@unifr.ch
    </description>
    <where>University of Fribourg (CH)</where>
    <when>2024-09-16</when>
    <link>https://www.unifr.ch/philosophie/de/departement/offene-stellen.html</link>
    <deadline>2024-10-31</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>Lectureship positions in Bath</title>
    <number>unspecified</number>
    <type>Tenure/Permanent</type>
    <description>
        The Department of Computer Science at the University of Bath has vacancies for academic appointments across its four main research groups:

        https://www.bath.ac.uk/campaigns/join-the-department-of-computer-science/

        This includes the Mathematical Foundations of Computation group, where we are particularly looking for individuals with research interests in areas around formal mathematics and computer assisted reasoning, including but not limited to:

        - proof assistants (e.g. Agda, Coq, Isabelle, Lean)

        - certified mathematical libraries

        - logical systems, proof theory and type theory

        - certified programming and program synthesis

        - automated reasoning

        - applications of AI and machine learning to formal mathematics

        The official job announcement and online application form can be found here:

        For any questions about the post or the recruitment process, please contact James Davenport (masjhd AT bath.ac.uk) or Thomas Powell (trjp20 AT bath.ac.uk).

        Interviews are planned to take place on the 25, 26, 27 November and 2 and 3 December 2024.
    </description>
    <where>University of Bath (UK)</where>
    <when>2024-09-16</when>
    <link>https://www.bath.ac.uk/jobs/Vacancy.aspx?ref=ED11636</link>
    <deadline>2024-10-15</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>Post-Doctoral Position in Non-Deterministic Semantics and Algebraization of Logics (Campinas, Brazil)</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>Postdoc</type>
    <description>
        Post-doctoral position (12 months, renewable for 12 months).
        Supervisor: Prof. Marcelo E. Coniglio

        Full description of the position available on the webpage of the project (see Open Post-doc Position in the top-left).
    </description>
    <where>Centre for Logic, Epistemology and the History of Science (CLE) at University of Campinas (UNICAMP)</where>
    <when>2024-09-13</when>
    <link>https://groupfortheoreticalandappliedlogic.my.canva.site/ratiolog2</link>
    <deadline>2024-10-02</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>PostDoc position in Bordeaux (FR)</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type> Postdoc </type>
    <description>
        The LaBRI research lab based at the University of Bordeaux is currently seeking highly 
        motivated candidates with excellent academic records and experience in knowledge 
        representation and reasoning (esp. ontologies, description logics, inconsistency
        and uncertainty handling), database theory, data quality and/or logic in CS to join 
        the Ratio team (ratio.labri.fr/) and take part in the INTENDED AI Chair (intended.labri.fr). 

        We currently have an opening for a 13-month postdoc position.The recruited person will 
        collaborate with myself and other project members on foundational research related to the 
        project's overall theme of developing principled methods for handling imperfect 
        (inconsistent, inconsistent, and/or uncertain) data, by exploiting declarative knowledge 
        and reasoning.  Generally speaking, this will involve the definition of formal frameworks 
        for repairing and querying imperfect data, the study of the computational complexity of the 
        associated reasoning tasks, and the development of reasoning algorithms (note that 
        implementation of developed algorithms is not required, but could be undertaken if desired).

        The precise research topics can be adapted to some degree to take into account the specific 
        background and interests of the hired researcher, so brilliant candidates with an interest for 
        the overall project topic should not hesitate to apply!
    </description>
    <where>Aix-Marseille Université</where>
    <when>2024-09-11</when>
    <link> http://intended.labri.fr/documents/postdoc-intended-2024.pdf </link>
    <deadline>2024-09-25</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>PostDoc position in Marseille (FR)</title>
    <number>2</number>
    <type> Postdoc </type>
    <description>
        Applications are invited for two postdoctoral positions in quantum
        computing in the Computer Science Lab (LIS) at Aix-Marseille Université.
        Those positions are funded by the PEPR EPIQ, a national action centered
        around all aspects of quantum software.

        The successful candidates will join the Laboratoire d'Informatique et
        des Systèmes (LIS), located in the Luminy campus in Marseille, just by
        the Calanques national park. They will participate in the research
        activities of the growing and enthusiastic community that has developed
        around quantum computing, in the beautiful Luminy technology hub. They
        will also interact with the Marseille Centre for Theoretical Physics and
        with the Marseille mathematics institute (I2M).

        Computer scientists have priority, but outstanding profiles in close
        disciplinary area (mathematics, theoretical physics) will be evaluated.

        1/ The first position for two years, in the areas of distributed quantum
        architectures and algorithms. The successful candidate will participate
        in the life of the Natural Computing Group (CANA), within the LIS.

        In addition, the winning candidate will get around 20k euros for his or
        her own missions (lectures, workshops, etc) and the possibility to
        collaborate on the direction of one of two PhDs that our team wants to
        recruit.

        Applications should be sent to giuseppe.dimolfetta@lis-lab.fr and should
        include a CV with a list of publications.

        2/ The second position is for 11 months, in the area of quantum
        programming languages and their semantics. The successful candidate will
        join the Logic, Semantics and Categories (LSC) group at LIS.

        Applications should be sent to pierre.clairambault@lis-lab.fr and should
        include a CV including a list of publications.

        Scientific interactions between both positions and other members of the
        local community will be encouraged.
    </description>
    <where>Aix-Marseille Université</where>
    <when>2024-09-07</when>
    <link> </link>
    <deadline>2024-10-15</deadline>
</POST> 

<POST>
    <title>PostDoc position in Torino</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type> Postdoc </type>
    <description>
        A call for applications for a one-year post-doc position in logic at the Department of Mathematics of the University of Torino has been published. 
        The intended research area of the position is in model theory or set theory, and related areas of mathematics. Salary is standard for Italian post-doc positions (€ 19.367 per year before taxes, N.B. the amount of taxes to be paid with this income is minimal). The position carries no teaching load. The position is for 12 months. The grant is part of the PRIN 2022 project 'Models, Sets and Classifications'. For further information, interested candidates can write to the PI of the project: gianluca.paolini@unito.it.
    </description>
    <where>Department of Mathematics of the University of Torino</where>
    <when>2024-08-22</when>
    <link>https://pica.cineca.it/unito/assegni-di-ricerca-unito-2024-ii-sdn/</link>
    <deadline>2024-09-23</deadline>
</POST> 

<POST>
    <title>PostDoc position in Logic in Milano</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type> Postdoc </type>
    <description>
        One postdoctoral position in Logic, focused on applications of logic to combinatorics, is available at the University of Milano, funded by the PRIN2022: Logical Methods in Combinatorics
    </description>
    <where>Department of Mathematics, University of Milano</where>
    <when>2024-07-31</when>
    <link>https://sites.google.com/uniroma1.it/lomec/open-positions</link>
    <deadline>2024-09-03</deadline>
</POST> 

<POST>
    <title>2-year PostDoc at Slovak Academy of Sciences</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>Postdoc</type>
    <description>
        L'Istituto di Filosofia dell'Accademia Slovacca delle Scienze ha aperto una posizione per ricercatrice/ricercatore postdoc con durata di due anni, rinnovabile in base alla valutazione del lavoro svolto. Il bando si trova al link qui sotto (la descrizione in inglese è in fondo alla pagina). La logica è tra le aree di maggiore rilievo per la selezione.
    </description>
    <where>Slovak Academy of Sciences</where>
    <when>2024-07-31</when>
    <link>http://tiny.cc/v2ybzz</link>
    <deadline>2024-08-31</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>Dottorato in Matematica, Fisica e Applicazioni per l'Ingegneria (Caserta)</title>
    <number>15</number>
    <type>PhD</type>
    <description>
        The graduate program offers 15 Ph.D. positions in every area of Mathematics, Physics and applications. 6 positions are reserved only to candidates with a degree from a foreign country (not Italy).
    </description>
    <where>Dipartimento di Matematica e Fisica</where>
    <when>2024-06-03</when>
    <link>https://www.unicampania.it/index.php/didattica/dottorati-di-ricerca/iscriversi-ad-un-dottorato</link>
    <deadline>2024-07-02</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>PhD program in Mathematics and applications (Genoa)</title>
    <number>8</number>
    <type>PhD</type>
    <description>
        There are 8 positions available. Candidates interested in Mathematical logic and willing to collaborate with the Genoa logic group are welcome to apply.
    </description>
    <where>Department of mathematics, University of Genoa</where>
    <when>2024-06-10</when>
    <link>https://unige.it/en/students/phd-programmes</link>
    <deadline>2024-07-09</deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>Postdoctoral Research Fellow at the University of Surrey (Guildford, UK)</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type>Postdoc</type>
    <description>
        We are seeking to recruit a full-time postdoctoral researcher to work on one or more of the areas below:

        - emerging hardware architectures (weak memory, RDMA, persistent memory, CXL),
        - verification with interactive and automated reasoning tools,
        - proofs of safety / security properties,
        - programming languages,
        - concurrent and/or distributed algorithms and related topics.

        The position is funded by the UK Engineering and Physical Science Research Council (EPSRC) project:
        - Safe and secure COncurrent programming for adVancEd aRchiTectures (COVERT) (https://gow.epsrc.ukri.org/NGBOViewGrant.aspx?GrantRef=EP/X015149/1)

        The successful applicant will work in a multidisciplinary team, as well as a large team of academic (Imperial, Kent, Sheffield, MPI-SWS, Cornell, IMDEA, etc) and industrial collaborators (Arm, NVIDIA, Galois), researchers and PhD students.

        Applicants must have or be close to obtaining a PhD in Computer Science.

        *** Further Details ***
        Post Type: Full time 
        Salary: £36,024 to £39,347 per annum
        Closing Date: 28th June 2024

        *** Enquiries ***
        For informal enquiries and further information please contact Brijesh Dongol at b.dongol@surrey.ac.uk or Gregory Chockler at g.chockler@surrey.ac.uk.
    </description>
    <where>University of Surrey</where>
    <when> 2024-06-03</when>
    <link>https://jobs.surrey.ac.uk/Vacancy.aspx?id=14085</link>
    <deadline> 2024-06-28 </deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>Fully funded PhD position on Axiomatic Definitions (Aix-en-Provence/Marseille, Francia)</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type> PhD </type>
    <description>
        Fully funded PhD position in "Axiomatic definitions. Criteria of adequacy and typologies of definitions in axiomatic theories of 19th and 20th centuries". Centre Gilles Gaston Granger, University of Aix-Marseille. Part of the ANR project AXDEF led by Paola Cantù.
    </description>
    <where>Centre Gilles Gaston Granger, University of Aix-Marseille</where>
    <when> 2024-05-29 </when>
    <link>https://emploi.cnrs.fr/Offres/Doctorant/UMR7304-PAOCAN-001/Default.aspx?lang=EN</link>
    <deadline> 2024-06-03 </deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>Three 2-year postdocs (Milano, IT)</title>
    <number>3</number>
    <type> Postdoc </type>
    <description>
        The Logic Uncertainty Computation and Information (LUCI) Lab at the University of Milan is seeking applications for   
        Three 2-year postdoctoral positions 
        funded by the Italian Ministry of University and Research (MUR) under the FIS1 Advanced Grant Reasoning with Data (ReDa)  led by Hykel Hosni 

        Deadline for application: 4 June 2024 
        Expected starting date:  1 September 2024 (negotiable)

        The appointments. Appointments will be made in either of the work packages below. Please specify in your application which WP would suit you best. Each candidate can put in one application only.  There are no teaching duties attached to the posts, and proficiency in Italian is not required. 
        Work package 1:  Non-monotonic formalisation of data-driven inference.
        The appointee is expected to work on the identification of suitable constraints for consequence relations capable of expressing salient patterns of data-driven inference. (The background and general idea are discussed informally here https://projects.illc.uva.nl/lgc/seminar/2023/03/lira-session-hykel-hosni/) . 
        Candidates for this work package must have a strong background in logic, acquired through a Master and a PhD in any of the relevant paths, including and possibly combining, Mathematics, Philosophy, and Computer Science. Familiarity with the preferential approach to nonmonotonic reasoning is a plus. Applicants are also expected to be conversant with elementary probability and statistics. 
        Work package 2:  Logic for the methodology of data-intensive and AI-driven science
        The appointee is expected to identify suitable roles for logical methods in the construction of a scientific methodology capable of encompassing AI-driven science. Logicians have traditionally followed Tarski in restricting the applicability of logic to the methodology of deductive sciences. In the age of data-intensive and machine-learning-driven science, this is overly restrictive both for logic and for science. To overcome this, the appointee will pin down patterns reasoning from any area of data-intensive and AI-driven science (preferably biology) and work towards their logical formalisation.
        Candidates for this work package must have a strong background in logic or philosophy of science, preferably both, acquired through a Master and a PhD in any of the relevant subject. Familiarity with the methodological and epistemological questions revolving around “big data” are a definite plus. Applicants are also expected to be conversant with the current literature on AI for scientific research, including explainable AI. Familiarity with the history of logic from Boole onwards is desirable.
        Work package 3:  The construction of probabilistic evidence in rare cancers
        The successful candidate is expected to work on methodologically rigorous approaches to the personalisation of probability in clinical decision-making about rare cancers. The key goal is to put forward principled ways to come up with patient-specific, meaningful, probabilities from data about “the average patient” arising in clinical studies. Since this work package will contribute to developing decision-theoretic tools to be used at the patient's bedside, the appointed researcher will be based at the Istituto Nazionale Tumori in Milan, and will work in close collaboration with the Biostatistics for Clinical Research, Sarcomas, and Head-and-Neck Cancers Units.   
        Applicants for this WP must have a strong background in medical statistics, clinical epidemiology and probability applied to those fields, acquired through any relevant postgraduate degree. Familiarity with medical decision making and the construction of probabilistic and statistical evidence is a definite plus.

        How to apply
        Please read carefully the official call for the posts, which is available in Italian and in English at 
        https://www.unimi.it/it/ricerca/ricerca-lastatale/fare-ricerca-da-noi/assegni-e-borse/bandi-assegni-di-ricerca/bando-di-tipo-b-prof-hosni-id-6648
    </description>
    <where>UNIMI</where>
    <when> 2024-05-29 </when>
    <link>https://luci.unimi.it/open-positions/</link>
    <deadline> 2024-06-04 </deadline>
</POST>

<POST>
    <title>Chaire de Professeur Junior (Clermont-Ferrand, France)</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type> Tenure/Permanent </type>
    <description>
        Un poste de "Chaire de Professeur Junior" va être ouvert pour la rentrée prochaine au Laboratoire de Mathématiques Blaise Pascal de l'Université Clermont Auvergne (avec comité de sélection en septembre, et prise de fonction en novembre). Il sera publié prochainement sur Galaxie, et les candidatures seront ouvertes jusqu'à fin juin. Le profil recherché est en "Algèbre et théorie des représentations", mais toutes les candidatures dans des domaines connexes pouvant s'intégrer au laboratoire (notamment topologie, théorie des nombres, théorie des groupes, analyse harmonique non commutative) seront étudiées avec attention.
        
        [Consultare la scadenza sul sito!]
    </description>
    <where>Université Clermont Auvergne</where>
    <when> 2024-05-22 </when>
    <link>https://lmbp.uca.fr/emplois/index.php</link>
    <deadline> 2024-06-30 </deadline>
</POST> 

<POST>
    <title>PhD program in Mathematics (Torino, Italy)</title>
    <number>7</number>
    <type> PhD </type>
    <description>
        There are 7 positions with fellowship and one of them is specifically reserved for candidates with a foreign master degree. It is possible to have joint supervision with a partner university
    </description>
    <where>Università di Torino</where>
    <when> 2024-05-22 </when>
    <link>https://www.dottorato.unito.it/do/home.pl/View?doc=Bando_XL_ciclo.html</link>
    <deadline> 2024-06-20 </deadline>
</POST> 

<POST>
    <title>PhD program in Mathematics and Physics (Udine, Italy)</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type> PhD </type>
    <description>
        In 2024 we are especially interested in students willing to work in set theory (potential supervisor Vincenzo Dimonte) and connections with dynamical systems (potential supervisor Giovanni Panti). Udine's Mathematical Logic group consists also of one post-doc researcher and two active PhD students (two others will obtain their degrees in 2024). You can contact any of us if you have further queries about possible scientific projects. For administrative information please contact dottorato.rice@uniud.it
    </description>
    <where>Università di Udine</where>
    <when> 2024-05-22 </when>
    <link>https://www.dmif.uniud.it/dottorato/smf/</link>
    <deadline> 2024-06-20 </deadline>
</POST> 

<POST>
    <title>PhD programs (Lucca, Italy)</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type> PhD </type>
    <description>
        Highly motivated candidates interested in doing philosophical research in a multidisciplinary environment are invited to apply online for scholarships offered by the Cognitive, Computational and Social Neurosciences (CCSN) and Economics, Analytics and Decision Sciences (EADS) doctoral programs at the IMT School for Advanced Studies Lucca (www.imtlucca.it).
        The successful candidates will join the MInD (Models, Inferences, and Decisions) group within the MoMiLab research unit. The ideal candidate will have a strong background in philosophy of science, epistemology, or logic and be interested in multidisciplinary work at the interface between philosophy, cognitive (neuro)science, and (behavioral) economics. Relevant research areas include general and formal philosophy of science, formal and social epistemology, philosophy of the cognitive and behavioral sciences, and theoretical and empirical models of expert judgment and reasoning (see the MInD page for more detail).
        The positions consist of a 3-year studentship of 16.243 euros per year (tax free, social security withholding), free housing in the School's accessible campus in the historical town of Lucca, free access to the canteen, library and other facilities on campus, additional funds for research and international mobility.
    </description>
    <where>IMT School for Advanced Studies Lucca</where>
    <when> 2024-05-26 </when>
    <link>https://www.imtlucca.it/en/phd/information-for-students</link>
    <deadline> 2024-06-20 </deadline>
</POST> 

<POST>
    <title>Assegno di Ricerca (Milano, Italy)</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type> Postdoc </type>
    <description>Assegno di Ricerca di 18 mesi (supervisor Pr. Ghilardi)</description>
    <where>Università di Milano</where>
    <when> 2024-05-26 </when>
    <link>https://www.unimi.it/it/ricerca/fare-ricerca-da-noi/assegni-di-ricerca/bandi-assegni-di-ricerca</link>
    <deadline> 2024-06-26 </deadline>
</POST> 

<POST>
    <title>PhD in Proof Theory (Brighton, UK)</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type> PhD </type>
    <description>
    The Department of Informatics at the University of Sussex (Brighton, UK) invites applications for highly motivated candidates interested in PhD positions in Logic (Proof Theory).
    The ideal candidate has a Master's degree in Mathematics, Computer Science or Philosophy with experience in Logic (preferably in Proof Theory). 
    The position has a duration of 3.5 years ideally starting in September 2024.
    The hired candidate will be part of the Foundations of Software Systems group ( https://www.sussex.ac.uk/foss/ ), a dynamic group in Theoretical Computer Science which is currently growing and has recently hired various young researchers.

    The project aims at studying the problem of proof equivalence and its applications.
    The problem of proof equivalence, which recently came to the forefront after the discovery of the 24th Hilbert problem, deals with deciding whether two logical arguments should be considered as the same proof, providing theoretical foundations for notions of program equivalences.
    To this end, the project will investigate novel notions of proof equivalence in various logical systems through the lens of proof theory. Emphasis will be given to the study of proof systems allowing canonical representations of proofs (e.g., Hughes' combinatorial proofs and Girard's proof nets). Moreover, the project plans to establish connections between proof equivalence and games, both in the sense of dialogical games (Lorenz and Lorenzen) and game semantics (Abramsky, Hyland and Ong).
    According to the interest of the candidate, applications to interoperability and usability of automated theorem prover and proof assistant, or applications to the theory of programming languages may be investigated.


    Applicants interested in the study of proof theory are encouraged to get in touch with Dr. Matteo Acclavio for additional information and informal inquiries.
    </description>
    <where>University of Sussex</where>
    <when> 2024-05-03 </when>
    <link>https://www.sussex.ac.uk/study/fees-funding/phd-funding/view/1735-PhD-Informatics-Scholarship-in-Proof-Theory </link>
    <deadline> 2024-06-06 </deadline>
</POST> 

<POST>
    <title>PhD in Type Theory (Nantes, France)</title>
    <number>1</number>
    <type> PhD </type>
    <description>
        The Gallinette team, hosted by Nantes University, advertises a 3-year PhD position in type theory.
        The position is financed by the ERC (European Research Council) project Fresco, coordinated by Assia Mahboubi. 
        Any candidate with a Master degree in mathematics or computer science and a scientific interest in the topic of the PhD project is encouraged to apply.
        The application should contain a motivation letter, an academic CV, and the contact information of two academic references (name, e-mail, and connection to the applicant). 
        Expected start date: 1 October 2024 (negotiable)
    </description>
    <where>Nantes University, Gallinette team</where>
    <when> 2024-05-01 </when>
    <link>https://recrutement.inria.fr/public/classic/fr/offres/2024-07624</link>
    <deadline> 2024-06-25 </deadline>
</POST>


</postsArchive>
